[
    {
        "question": "What temperature does water boil at?",
        "optionA": "50 degrees Celcius",
        "optionB": "25 degrees Celcius",
        "optionC": "100 degrees Celcius",
        "optionD": "150 degrees Celcius",
        "answer": "100 degrees Celcius"
    },

    {
        "question": "When an hausa man marries a Yoruba woman, we call it ______________marriage",
        "optionA": "Intra-ethnic",
        "optionB": "Ethnic",                          
        "optionC": "Inter-ethnic",
        "optionD": "Wedding",
        "answer": "Inter-ethnic"
    },

    {
        "question": "_____________ colonized Nigeria",                        
        "optionA": " Italy",
        "optionB": "Ghana",
        "optionC": "Britian",
        "optionD": "America",
        "answer": "Britian"
    },

    {
        "question": "Which is the only mammal that can’t jump?",
        "optionA": "Dog",
        "optionB": "Elephant",
        "optionC": "Goat",
        "optionD": "Lion",
        "answer": "Elephant"
    },

    {
        "question": "Nigeria got her independence on __________________",              
        "optionA": "October  1st 1960",
        "optionB": "October 1st 1860",
        "optionC": "October 1st 1760",
        "optionD": "October 1st 1660",
        "answer": "October  1st 1960"
    },

    {
        "question": "What colour is a panda?",
        "optionA": "Green and Yellow",
        "optionB": "Blue and Red",
        "optionC": "Green and White",
        "optionD": "Black and White",
        "answer": "Black and White"
    },

    {
        "question": "Where is the smallest bone in the human body?",
        "optionA": "The Chest",
        "optionB": "The Ear",
        "optionC": "The Legs",
        "optionD": "The Hands",
        "answer": "The Ear"
    },

    {
        "question": "What does the roman numeral C represent?",
        "optionA": "100",
        "optionB": "10",
        "optionC": "10,000",
        "optionD": "1,000,000",
        "answer": "100"
    },

    {
        "question": "Christianity introduced ______________",                                    
        "optionA": "Monogamy",
        "optionB": "Polygamy",
        "optionC": " Large",
        "optionD": "Extended",
        "answer": "Monogamy"
    },

    {
        "question": "Inter-ethnic marriage is between couples from different __________ group.",                 
        "optionA": "Religion",
        "optionB": "Family",
        "optionC": "School",
        "optionD": "Ethnic",
        "answer": "Ethnic"
    },

    {
        "question": "What’s the most important book in the Moslem religion?",
        "optionA": "The Koran",
        "optionB": "The Dictionary",
        "optionC": "The Bible",
        "optionD": "The Chemistry text Book",
        "answer": "The Koran"
    },

    {
        "question": "What’s the capital of Ethiopia?",
        "optionA": "Cape Town",
        "optionB": "San Francisco",
        "optionC": "Addis Ababa",
        "optionD": "Syndey",
        "answer": "Addis Ababa"
    },

    {
        "question": "How many squares are there on a chess board?",
        "optionA": "128",
        "optionB": "64",
        "optionC": "32",
        "optionD": "256",
        "answer": "64"
    },

    {
        "question": "Marriage takes place in the following place except _______",               
        "optionA": " Hospital",
        "optionB": "Church",
        "optionC": "Mosque",
        "optionD": "Traditional",
        "answer": " Hospital"
    },

    {
        "question": "What are the first three words of the bible?",
        "optionA": "be with everyone",
        "optionB": "Again Jesus asked",
        "optionC": "In the beginning",
        "optionD": "At that time",
        "answer": "In the beginning"
    },

    {
        "question": "sThe award of honour is given by the  ___________of a country.",
        "optionA": "Governor",
        "optionB": "Minister  ",                      
        "optionC": "President",
        "optionD": "Senator",
        "answer": "President"
    },

    {
        "question": "Tolerance is an act of _______________.",
        "optionA": "Disagreement",
        "optionB": "Fighthing",
        "optionC": "Lying ",
        "optionD": "Endurance",
        "answer": "Endurance"
    },
    {
        "question": "___________security management is the means by which a person ensure adequate security of himself",
        "optionA": "Individual",
        "optionB": "Social ",                                  
        "optionC": "Relationship",
        "optionD": "Personal",
        "answer": "Personal"
    }, 

    {
        "question": "Any action that is morally wrong is known as_______________",
        "optionA": "Punishment",
        "optionB": "Crime",
        "optionC": "Penalty",                                                   
        "optionD": "Suicide",
        "answer": "Crime"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pain that somebody is made to suffer because he/she committed a crime is known as ____________",
        "optionA": "Attitude",                                                            
        "optionB": "Punishment",
        "optionC": "Control",
        "optionD": "Insult",
        "answer": "Punishment"
    },
    {
        "question": "Fake drugs includes drug that are not ____________",
        "optionA": "Genuine",
        "optionB": "Grinded",
        "optionC": "Coloured",
        "optionD": "Imported",                                            
        "answer": "Genuine"
    },
    {
        "question": "_______________is the act of taking or stealing somebody’s property",
        "optionA": "Forgery",
        "optionB": "Rape",
        "optionC": "Theft",
        "optionD": "Fraud",                                                           
        "answer": "Theft"
    },

    {
        "question": "The highest national honour award in Nigeria is ______________",
        "optionA": "CFR",
        "optionB": "CON",
        "optionC": "CFU",
        "optionD": "GCON",                                             
        "answer": "GCON"
    },
    {
        "question": "Union between a man and a woman to ______ together as husband and wife is called marriage.",
        "optionA": "Life",
        "optionB": "Die",
        "optionC": "Live",                                        
        "optionD": "Leave",
        "answer": "Live"
    },
    {
        "question": "An award given to somebody  who has contributed to national development is known as__________",
        "optionA": "National Award",
        "optionB": "Country Award",                                                    
        "optionC": " State Award",
        "optionD": "Presidental Award",
        "answer": "National Award"
    }
]